Felipe Pereira

Software Developer | Data Scientist

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Email

Summary

Developer committed to problem-solving and crafting innovative solutions. Over 3 years of experience. Specialized in Python and its frameworks. Worked with frameworks like Django, FastAPI and Flask, and libraries such as Pandas, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, Requests.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript
- Libraries and frameworks: Django, FastAPI, Flask, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV
- Frontend: TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
- Database: SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Professional Experience

Developer and Instructor | Trybe | November 2021 - Present

- Development of full-stack web applications using Django and Flask.
- Teaching of full-stack web concepts and computer science fundamentals, data structures, and algorithms.
- Close collaboration with other teams to implement effective features.

Teacher - Physics/Science/Programming | Pitágoras | June 2018 - December 2021

- Content creation and teaching of physics, science, and programming classes.
- Handling of seven classes with up to 40 students each.

Teacher - Physics/Science/Programming | Palomar | June 2016 - December 2020

- Content creation and teaching of physics, science, and programming classes.
- Handling of 4 classes with up to 30 students each.

Education

- Postgraduate Studies in Software Engineering | Faculdade Metropolitana | Still in Progress
- Postgraduate Studies in Database Administration | Faculdade Metropolitana | Still in Progress
- Master's in Nuclear Engineering | Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais | Completed in June 2019
- Bachelor's in Physics | Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais | Completed in June 2016

Languages

Portuguese (Native) | English (Advanced) | Spanish (Basic) | German (Basic)